[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Salinization occurs when the irrigation water accumulated in the soil evaporates, leaving behind salts and minerals. What are the effects of salinization on the irrigated land ?",
    "option": [
      "It greatly increases the crop production",
      "It makes some soils impermeable",
      "It raises the water table",
      "t fills the air spaces in the soil with water"
    ],
    "correctAns": "It makes some soils impermeable",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Assertion (A) : Laterite soils are red in color and coarse in texture.Reason (R) : Laterite soils contain high concentrations of silica and calcium carbonate.",
    "option": [
      "Both (A) and (R) are individually true and (R) is the correct explanation of (A)",
      "Both (A) and (R) are individually true but (R) is not the correct explanation of (A)",
      "(A) is true but (R) is false",
      "(A) is false but (R) is true"
    ],
    "correctAns": "(A) is true but (R) is false",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Non-commerical pastoral nomadism is a way of life in the",
    "option": [
      "Velds of South Africa",
      "Steppes of Mongolia",
      "Prairies of Canada",
      "Australian downs"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Steppes of Mongolia",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "India is the world's largest producer of",
    "option": ["Rice", "Wheat", "Millet", "Cotton"],
    "correctAns": "Millet",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Which of the following techniques is useful for predicting the wheat yield ?",
    "option": ["Regression", "Chi-square", "Simulation", "Correlation"],
    "correctAns": "Regression",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Salinization occurs when the irrigation water accumulated in the soil evaporates, leaving behind salts and minerals. What are the effects of salinization on the irrigated land ?",
    "option": [
      "It greatly increases the crop production",
      "It makes some soils impermeable",
      "It raises the water table",
      "t fills the air spaces in the soil with water"
    ],
    "correctAns": "It makes some soils impermeable",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Assertion (A) : Laterite soils are red in colour and coarse in texture.Reason (R) : Laterite soils contain high concentrations of silica and calcium carbonate.",
    "option": [
      "Both (A) and (R) are individually true and (R) is the correct explanation of (A)",
      "Both (A) and (R) are individually true but (R) is not the correct explanation of (A)",
      "(A) is true but (R) is false",
      "(A) is false but (R) is true"
    ],
    "correctAns": "(A) is true but (R) is false",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Non-commerical pastoral nomadism is a way of life in the",
    "option": [
      "Velds of South Africa",
      "Steppes of Mongolia",
      "Prairies of Canada",
      "Australian downs"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Steppes of Mongolia",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "India is the world's largest producer of",
    "option": ["Rice", "Wheat", "Millet", "Cotton"],
    "correctAns": "Millet",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which of the following techniques is useful for predicting the wheat yield ?",
    "option": ["Regression", "Chi-square", "Simulation", "Correlation"],
    "correctAns": "Regression",
    "userAnswer": null,
    "visited": false
  }
]
